sd203.org 2011-12-25

# Privacy Policy - Naperville Community Unit School District 203

Privacy Policy

Information collected at www.naperville203.org  
Does District 203 share the information it recieves/collects?  
How secure is information about me?  
About children and Internet Safety  
Videotaping and photographing of students  
Links to third party and/or co-branded websites  
District electronic communications guidelines  
Message boards/forums  
Conditions of use, notices and revisions

The following states the privacy policy of Naperville Community Unit School District 203 (“District 203”) regarding the privacy rights of the visitors and users of the District 203 web sites (herein collectively referred to as the “Site”). We respect your concern over your right to privacy and for a secure online experience.

**By accessing** **www.naperville203.org** **and its affiliated websites, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.**

Information Collected at www.naperville203.org

The information we collect from District 203 visitors and users of our Site allows us to personalize and continually improve your online experience, making it easier and more enjoyable. The following identifies the types of information we gather:

Automatic Information

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many Sites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses our Site. Cookies are pieces of data your web browser stores on your hard drive to enable our systems to recognize you and your browser. Most web browsers automatically accept these cookies, and will also allow you to instruct your browser to prevent the use of cookies. However, if you disable this feature, certain aspects of our Site may not function properly.

Information You Give Us

We receive and may store any information you enter on our Site or give us in any other way. At times, we specifically ask for information about you when you register for or to use certain services or functionalities. We may require certain information \- such as name, Internet address or screen name, mailing address, phone number, etc - in order to provide that service or functionality to you.

Does District 203 Share the Information it Receives/Collects?

District 203 may use reputable third parties to manage activities available on our Site such as web hosting, database management, and application processing. These parties may have access to personally identifiable information submitted by visitors and/or users as a result of these activities. District 203 instructs these third parties to use personally identifiable information only for the specific purpose for which it is collected, and not to sell, market or transfer such information to other entities except as needed to provide the designated services.

District 203 posts and displays certain personally identifiable information about its employees, administrative staff and committee members on our Site. District 203 allows users to post certain information about themselves in certain areas of the Site.

District 203 may use personally identifiable information in aggregate form to make our Site better and more responsive to the needs of our users and visitors. This statistical compilation and analysis of information may also be used by District 203 or be provided to others, in an aggregate format, for marketing, educational, quality control or research purposes.

We release account and other personal information when we believe its release is appropriate to comply with any law; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other applicable agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of District 203, our employees, our representatives, or others.

This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection.

Back to top

How Secure Is Information About Me?

District 203 maintains appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personally identifiable information submitted to our Site, and periodically reviews and updates its security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Although District 203 strives to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information you may transmit to us or from our online products and services. Once we do receive your transmission, however, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

Back to top

About Children and Internet Safety

District 203 is concerned about the safety of children when they use the Internet. Pursuant to the Children’s Internet Protection Act (CIPA) of 2001, District 203 will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. CIPA mandates that filtering is in place to block offensive content on school and library computers, including obscene pictures, pornographic images and content harmful to minors.

District 203 follows the guidelines of Illinois Public Act 095-0869 regarding Internet Safety Curriculum. This law states that: “Beginning with the 2009-2010 school year, a school district must incorporate into the school curriculum a component on Internet safety to be taught at least once each school year to students in grade 3 or above.”

The following areas are covered:

  1. Safe and responsible use of social networking websites, chat rooms, electronic mail, bulletin boards, instant messaging, and other means of communication on the Internet.
  2. Recognizing, avoiding, and reporting online solicitations of students, their classmates, and their friends by sexual predators.
  3. Risks of transmitting personal information on the Internet.
  4. Recognizing and avoiding unsolicited or deceptive communications received online.
  5. Recognizing and reporting online harassment and cyber-bullying.
  6. Reporting illegal activities and communications on the Internet.
  7. Copyright laws on written materials, photographs, music, and video.

Back to top

Videotaping and Photographing of Students

During the course of the school year, your children will be involved in many school activities that may be captured on video or photographed for sharing and/or placement on the school or District web pages.

Videotaping and photographing of students in special education settings for non-educational purposes will be authorized only with parental consent. Outside of special education settings, students may be videotaped or photographed by parents, observers, school employees, students and news media personnel from time to time while participating in school activities.

If you desire that your student not be videotaped or photographed in these circumstances, outside of special education settings, please contact the principal to discuss reasonable restrictions. Denial of Permission forms requesting that students' images and/or work not be reproduced in the media are to be sent to the school principal.

Back to top

Links to Third Party and/or Co-Branded Websites

District 203 has and will continue to establish relationships with other community and business entities, which also may have web sites to inform or promote their services or products. District 203 will at times allow users visiting the District 203 Site to link directly to these third party web sites. However, District 203 is not responsible for the privacy practices and content of these third party web sites. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement and user terms and conditions whenever interacting with, and prior to providing any personal information to, any third party web site.

Back to top

District Electronic Communications Guidelines  
  
District 203 Acceptable Use Guidelines for Electronic Communications

District 203 employees/volunteers have been utilizing technology for many years in delivering upon our mission to educate students to be self-directed learners, collaborative workers, complex thinkers, quality producers, and community contributors. In addition to their educational pursuits, today’s students, and those in future years, are and will be deeply engaged in electronic forms of communications and associated technologies for daily interaction with friends, family, community and larger social networks.

Many District employees/volunteers have also utilized technologies such as email, websites, blogs, text messaging and use of social media websites such as Facebook, Twitter, and more, to communicate with similar groups for personal interactions. These forms of communication are dynamic, mobile, and quickly reach their targeted audience through technologies that have become an integral part of many individuals’ lives.

As these technologies continue to advance at a rapid pace, they can become sources of significant benefit to the educational process when integrated into District 203's scholastic delivery model. While continual evolution will undoubtedly occur in this area, it is our goal in issuing these guidelines to increase awareness and understanding of these technologies as well as ensure that their use for District business meets the public and professional standards for communicating with students that we set for ourselves in District 203.

These guidelines are designed for the purpose of:

  * Clarifying acceptable ways to use electronic communication tools when communicating with students, peers, and community members for District related business.
  * Raising awareness of the positive and negative outcomes that may result in using these tools when interacting with the targeted audience.
  * Establishing the appropriate levels of approval for the use and integration of these technologies for educational benefits aligned with our District mission.

This document includes a visual matrix that uses color coding to help clarify the District's position related to various forms of electronic communication. In the visual matrix individuals or groups are categorized into either communication originators or communication receivers (also referred to as the targeted audience) to help with interpretation of the guidelines.

Back to top

Message Boards/Forums

Please remember that any information you may disclose in blogs, online discussion forums, wikis, message boards, chats or other public areas of our Site or the Internet becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in public disussion areas.

Back to top

Conditions of Use, Notices, and Revisions

If you choose to visit or use the District 203 Site, any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our [Terms of Use Policy,](http://policy.microscribepub.com/cgi-bin/om_isapi.dll?clientID=45726&advquery=%22Access%20to%20Electronic%20Networks%22&depth=2&headingswithhits=on&hitsperheading=on&infobase=naperville.nfo&record={D8B}&softpage=PL_frame) including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of the law of the state of Illinois. If you have any concern about your privacy while on the District 203 Site or with District 203 in general, please send a thorough description/explanation to the [Webmaster](mailto:info@naperville203.org?subject=Naperville203.org%20Privacy%20Policy%20) so that we may review it and take any actions deemed necessary. As technology changes constantly, this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use Policy may change as well. Use of information we gather now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use. Please check our Site frequently for recent changes or additions.

Back to top

_Revised 8/11/2011_
